John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
John A. Holmes Papers
1930 -- 1960
1813 -- 1998
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Holmes, John
MS007
23.95 Linear Feet
1 Audiovisual Object(s)
127 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into fourteen series: Poetry; Works; Notebooks; Letters by Holmes; Letters to Holmes; New England Poetry Club; Chautauqua notebooks; Printed works; Scrapbooks; Photographs; Personal and business records; Robert Frost collection; Writings about Holmes; Family materials.
Custodial History
The bulk of the material was donated to Tufts by Holmes' widow, with the exception of the Frost Collection, which was trasferred to Tufts by Holmes' will. Additional materials were collected by John Ciardi, a student of Holmes and poet in his own right, and given to Tufts piecemeal. Some materials were sent directly to the archives and were added to the collection by past librarians and curators of the collection.
The bust of Robert Frost (former item MS007.012.063.00001) was a Art Gallery item AI 17800, and the loan was returned to them on May 7, 2018, by Collection Management Archivist Adrienne Pruitt.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of typescript and handwritten manuscripts of poems and other writings, correspondence, notebooks, scrapbooks compiled by Holmes, family materials, and book and manuscript materials pertaining to Robert Frost, collected by Holmes. The bulk of the material dates from the period 1930-1960, when Holmes was most active in his writing career, and consists of manuscripts of poems, including many in multiple revisions. Correspondents include Robert Frost, Archibald MacLeish, and May Sarton.
Biographical / Historical
John Albert Holmes, Jr. (1904-1962) was born in Somerville, Massachusetts, on January 6, 1904 to John Holmes, Sr., an engineer, and Mary (Murdock) Holmes. After attending Somerville public schools, John Holmes entered Tufts College in the fall of 1925. John Cousens, president of Tufts University, heard Holmes read his class poem at his high school graduation, and, impressed with the young poet, took Holmes under his wing during Holmes' student years at Tufts. Holmes received his bachelor's degree in 1929 and throughout the following year attended graduate courses at Harvard while serving as an assistant in English at Tufts.
Holmes began his teaching career at Lafayette College in Easton, Pennsylvania, where he served as an Instructor of English during the years 1930-32. He later returned to Somerville and Tufts, joining the faculty of the Department of English as an Instructor in 1934. At Tufts, he advanced through the ranks of assistant and associate to a full professorship in 1960. He was honored with an honorary doctorate by the University in 1962.
Holmes achieved notable success as a poet and author during his lifetime. He published seven collections of poetry: Address to the Living (1937), Fair Warning (1939), Map of My Country (1943), Along the Row (1944), The Double Root (1950), The Symbols (1955), and The Fortune Teller (1961). His work appeared in numerous publications from literary journals to daily newspapers. Holmes wrote two books about the writing of poetry, The Poet's Work (1939) and Writing Poetry (1960), in addition to many essays and book reviews. Holmes was also an avid letter writer, and had active correspondence with family, friends, and other poets. Letter writing was part of his daily writing routine, and served as a warm-up of sorts for the work of writing verse.
Holmes devoted considerable effort to fostering the development of young and budding poets with whom he came into contact. In addition to teaching poetry and creative writing at Tufts, he taught poetry workshops at the Boston Center for Adult Education, and directed or participated in writers workshops at Tufts University, the University of New Hampshire at Durham, and the Chautauqua Writers Conference. Holmes also hosted an informal poetry circle with other Boston area poets in the 1950s, a group which included May Sarton, Anne Sexton, and others. This group met regularly at Holmes' residence in Medford to read and comment on each other's work.
In 1933, Holmes married his first wife, Sara Frances Ludlow, with whom he had one son, John Ludlow Holmes. After his first wife's death, he married Doris Kirk in 1948 and had another son, Evan Kirk Holmes, and a daughter, Margaret Nash Holmes. Holmes died June 22, 1962 following a long illness in Boston, Massachusetts.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Poets, American -- Massachusetts -- Archives.; Holmes, John, 1904-1962 -- Archives.; Tufts University -- Faculty -- Archives.; Faculty papers; Greater Boston arts
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  Poems by Holmes. Almost all are typescript originals of poems, and many have multiple revisions and annotations. The bulk of the material is from 1940-61. There was no indication of original order, so poems have been cataloged in the order in which they were filed by previous curators of the collection. The arrangement of the poems is generally chronological, with the earliest poems grouped at the beginning and later poems following, but because many poems were not dated, this arrangement is imprecise. For the most part, each poem is filed in its own folder, except for several binders of poems Holmes compiled which can be found in boxes 10 and 11. The poems in these binders have been preserved in the original order imposed by Holmes.
  An item record has been created for each poem as an intellectual work. This record includes information on the existence of any revisions and their locations. The term "revision" indicates that a version of the poem different from that which initially generated the record exists. Revision in this context does not necessarily imply a chronological progression of edits of a poem from first draft to final version, but rather indicates the existence of different versions of the same poem. Thus the item record for a poem could contain "revisions" which are in fact earlier versions of the poem.
  Full text of the poem is included in the item record. For poems with multiple revisions, the version which appeared to be the most complete was selected for scanning, though this version will not necessarily match the actual published version.
  Additional material was added to the Holmes collection in June 2009 by Laura Cutter. Items added to this series include copies of poems already existing in the collection and several new, unpublished poems. The duplicate poems were interfiled with the pre-existing copies. A statement was added to the notes field at the item level if the newly-added poem was inscribed, notated, or a different version than the other copies of the poem. One phonograph album of John Holmes reading his own poem, "A prayer on the night before Easter" was added to this collection. Materials that could not be interfiled into the collection were added at the end of the series in box 069. These materials include four previously unpublished poems: "Lines to ittle baby boy," "New woman in the house," "Nobody now has seen a real scarecrow," and "To Effa, with love." Also included are typed versions of Holmes' manuscripts and transcripts of poetry readings. Materials not included and subsequently deaccessioned were generally duplicate photocopies of poems already in the collection.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by poem number. Only the first instance of a poem is cataloged. Other versions and their physical location are noted in the poem's record. All notations listed in the description in the format "X:YYY" refers to Box X, Folder YYY.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - On hearing someone say that every possible subject has been covered in poetry, MS007.001.001.00001; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 001.
  - Reminder, MS007.001.001.00002; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Sonnet [To someone I know], MS007.001.001.00003; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 002. duplicate in 1:63
  - Low fog, MS007.001.001.00004; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - [Lines about a great space], MS007.001.001.00005; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 003. duplicate in 1:47
  - Sanctuary, MS007.001.001.00006; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 003. minor revisions in 1:71
  - To Joanne, MS007.001.001.00007; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 003. duplicate in 1:71
  - The soul's lonliness, MS007.001.001.00008; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 004.
  - You, who understood, MS007.001.001.00009; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 004. Revision in 9:071 is handwritten. Revision in 9:071
  - Morning, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00010; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 004. duplicate in 1:60
  - What things I can, 1925; MS007.001.001.00011; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 005. Revision in 8:067 dated May 6, 1924. Revision in 10:034, p. 91 is handwritten Published in Dawn: Second National Anthology of High School Verse (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1925) p. 1 Revisions in 1:43
  - The father, 1925; MS007.001.001.00012; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 005. Revision in 8:067 dated May 6, 1924. Duplicate in 10:034, p. 91 is handwritten. Published in Dawn: Second National Anthology of High School Verse (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1925) p. 30; Father: An Anthology of Verse (New York: Dutton, 1931) p. 110; New York Herald-Tribune, June 29 1930. Duplicate in 1:43
  - The gleam, 1924-05-04; MS007.001.001.00013; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 005. Annotated. Duplicate in 9:003 is dated May 4, 1924. Duplicate in 1:44
  - My tree, 1925; MS007.001.001.00014; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 005. Revision in 10:034, p. 90 is handwritten Published in Dawn: Second National Anthology of High School Verse (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1925) p. 15. The date has been estimated duplicate in 1:13
  - My little world, MS007.001.001.00015; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 006. revisions in 1:86
  - The vale impassable, MS007.001.001.00016; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 006. duplicate in 1:86
  - The forgotten hero, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00017; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 007. Revision located in 6:015 is handwritten. Revision located in 8:069 is handwritten. duplicate in 1:68
  - The garden, MS007.001.001.00018; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 007.
  - Verbosity, MS007.001.001.00019; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 008. Annotated
  - [Man], MS007.001.001.00020; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 009. Duplicate in 9:044 is handwritten. duplicates in 1:69 and 9:044
  - A monument, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00021; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 010. duplicate in 1:97
  - A death at evening, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00022; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 010. revisions in 1:100
  - Recipe for a journey, 1924-06-01; MS007.001.001.00023; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 010. duplicate in 1:98
  - Evening, MS007.001.001.00024; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 011. revisions in 1:75 and 9:073
  - From a window, 1925; MS007.001.001.00025; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 011. Duplicate in 1:055 is annotated. Revision in 8:072 is annotated. Published in Dawn: Second National Anthology of High School Verse (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1925) p. 32. The date has been estimated duplicates in 1:13 and 8:072
  - Sight and death, MS007.001.001.00026; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 011. revisions in 1:42
  - In the days when the eternal hills go down, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00027; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 012. minor revisions in 1:107
  - Something from the soft wind, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00028; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 012. duplicate in 1:107
  - Noon, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00029; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 012. revisions in 1:107
  - The moon, MS007.001.001.00030; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 012. duplicate in 1:41
  - In a time of misunderstanding, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00031; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 012. Annotated. Revision in 9:048 titled: A misunderstanding. Revision in 9:048 is dated July 1924. Revision in 9:048 is annotated. revisions 1:38, 1:105 and July 1924, 9:048
  - Demand, MS007.001.001.00032; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 013. minor revisions in 1:48 and duplicate in 8:072
  - The constant battle, MS007.001.001.00033; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 013. duplicates 1:48 and 8:072
  - [Sleepless], MS007.001.001.00034; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 014. revisions in 1:85
  - A prayer [A prayer on failing eyesight], 1923-04-23; MS007.001.001.00035; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 014. Revision in 1:085 titled "A prayer on failing eyesight" revision in 1:085
  - On being thankful, 1923-04-24; MS007.001.001.00036; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 014. duplicate in 1:85
  - Pleasant solitude, MS007.001.001.00037; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 014.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.001.00038; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Somehow, sometime, somewhere, MS007.001.001.00039; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 014. Revision in 10:034, p. 101 is handwritten. revision in 10:034, p. 101
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.001.00040; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The pines, MS007.001.001.00041; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A shield and a strong defence, MS007.001.001.00042; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 015. Annotated duplicates in 1:41 and 1:015
  - The high heart, MS007.001.001.00043; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 015. duplicate in 1:40
  - Bewilderment in church, MS007.001.001.00044; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 015. minor revisions in 1:40
  - Advice on success in writing poetry, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.001.00045; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 015. duplicate in 1:107
  - Pierrot, MS007.001.001.00046; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 016. revisions 1:62 and 9:040
  - Encouragement, MS007.001.001.00047; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 017.
  - Three wishes, MS007.001.001.00048; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Swinging, MS007.001.001.00049; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 017. Revision (handwritten) in 8:009 revision in 8:009
  - Tobacco and a pipe, MS007.001.001.00050; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Grandmother's parlor, MS007.001.001.00051; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 018.
  - Sailing, MS007.001.001.00052; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 018. Duplicate (Handwritten) of 8:009 duplicate in 8:009
  - O little sails, make haste!, MS007.001.001.00053; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 019.
  - Night, MS007.001.001.00054; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Walking on the beach, MS007.001.001.00055; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - From the Window, MS007.001.001.00056; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 020.
  - On the contemplation of vastness, MS007.001.001.00057; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 020. Duplicate in 8:092 is handwritten. duplicate in 8:092
  - The king passes by, 1923-06-04; MS007.001.001.00058; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 021.
  - Youth, MS007.001.001.00059; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 022. Revision in 8:119 is titled: To a youth. revision in 8:119
  - Beneath a tree, MS007.001.001.00060; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 022.
  - Beyond the hill, MS007.001.001.00061; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Books, MS007.001.001.00062; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 023.
  - To a statuette of a little girl, MS007.001.001.00063; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 024. Duplicate in 8:092 is handwritten. duplicate in 8:092
  - Wanderer's song, MS007.001.001.00064; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 024.
  - Joshua Peabody, MS007.001.001.00065; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 024. Annotated Published in Dawn: Second National Anthology of High School Verse (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1925) p. 48
  - Against poms and carelessness, MS007.001.001.00066; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The way of least resistance, 1923-05-08; MS007.001.001.00067; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 025. revisions in 1:84
  - Voice of the sea, 1923; MS007.001.001.00068; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 025. Published in Glimpses: A National Anthology of Secondary School Verse, 1923 (Middleboro, MA: n p, 1923) p. 25. The date has been estimated duplicate in 1:84
  - A letter unopened on my desk, 1923-05-04; MS007.001.001.00069; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 025. duplicate in 1:85
  - Fragments: Far horizon, MS007.001.001.00070; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 026.
  - Fragments: The inquiring mind, MS007.001.001.00071; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: The cigarette, MS007.001.001.00072; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: History repeats, MS007.001.001.00073; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: Yesterday, to-day, to-morrow, MS007.001.001.00074; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: After the forest fire, MS007.001.001.00075; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: Down to earth, MS007.001.001.00076; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 027.
  - Fragments: Butter side down, MS007.001.001.00077; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: A conversation, MS007.001.001.00078; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: Fear, MS007.001.001.00079; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: Inconsistency, MS007.001.001.00080; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Fragments: A secret laughter, MS007.001.001.00081; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - To a small boy learning to read, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00082; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 028. Duplicate in 1:070 is annotated. Duplicate in 1:028 is dated October 1923. minor revisions in 1:70 and duplicate, October 1923, in 1:028
  - Reading sonnets late at night, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00083; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 028. Duplicate in 1:028 is dated October 1923. minor revisions in 1:60 and duplicate, October 1923, 1:028
  - Autumn, 1923-10-01; MS007.001.001.00084; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 028. Duplicate in 1:028 is dated October 1923. duplicates 1:60 and October 1923, 1:028
  - Lonely, MS007.001.001.00085; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 029. duplicates in 1:38 and 1:029
  - Walking home at night, MS007.001.001.00086; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 029. duplicates in 1:40 and 1:029
  - A ship's figure-head, MS007.001.001.00087; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 029. Duplicate in 1:039 is annotated duplicates in 1:39 and 1:029
  - This house will never need, MS007.001.001.00088; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 030.
  - Conversation, MS007.001.001.00089; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Dusk falls down the roofs, MS007.001.001.00090; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Moment, MS007.001.001.00091; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Words for a minuet, 1923-08-07; MS007.001.001.00092; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 031. Annotated
  - Make yourself a way, 1925-08-29; MS007.001.001.00093; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 032. Annotated duplicate in 10:034, p. 86
  - Languor, MS007.001.001.00094; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 032. Annotated; revision in 7:080 revisions in 7:080 and 10:034, p. 86
  - A childish chant, MS007.001.001.00095; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 032. Annotated. Revision in 10:034, p. 101 is handwritten. revisions in 10:034, p. 86 and p. 101
  - Twice born, MS007.001.001.00096; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 032. revision in 10:034, p. 86
  - Suddenly I knew, MS007.001.001.00097; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 032. Annotated revision in 10:034, p. 86
  - Coming home from the library, MS007.001.001.00098; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 033.
  - The visitor, MS007.001.001.00099; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 034. revision in 8:118
  - Four Songs, MS007.001.001.00100; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 035. revision in 9:087
  - The willow tree, MS007.001.001.00101; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 036. revision in 9:008
  - Rhymes of a very small boy, MS007.001.001.00102; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 037.
  - Big enough, MS007.001.001.00103; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Baggage into the land of Nod, MS007.001.001.00104; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 038.
  - Song - Come again with me to Plymouth, MS007.001.001.00105; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 039.
  - Portrait, MS007.001.001.00106; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 040.
  - Portrait [The Great Man], MS007.001.001.00107; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 041. duplicate in 1:127
  - A hopeful lover, MS007.001.001.00108; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 041.
  - Portrait of a girl, 1934; MS007.001.001.00109; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 041. Published in American Poetry Journal, p. 7, February 1934; Hartford Daily Times, February 12 1935. The date has been estimated
  - Writing in the woods, MS007.001.001.00110; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Memory of A. L., MS007.001.001.00111; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 42. duplicate in 1:127
  - Portrait, MS007.001.001.00112; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 42.
  - The prisoner, MS007.001.001.00113; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The warehouseman, MS007.001.001.00114; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - A timid lover, 1924-05-06; MS007.001.001.00115; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 043. Revision in 8:067 dated May 6, 1924. revision in 8:067
  - Message to be found a hundred years hence, 1924-05-06; MS007.001.001.00116; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - What poetry is, 1924-05-04; MS007.001.001.00117; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 44. Revision in 9:003 is dated May 4, 1924. revision in 9:003
  - Wind on a hill, 1924-05-04; MS007.001.001.00118; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 044. Revision in 9:003 is dated May 4, 1924. revision in 9:003
  - Two o'clock, 1924-05-04; MS007.001.001.00119; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Song, MS007.001.001.00120; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 045.
  - Another sleeps, MS007.001.001.00121; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Portrait [His enemy], 1925-03-01; MS007.001.001.00122; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 045. Revision in 1:127 titled "His enemy" revision in 1:127
  - Portrait, MS007.001.001.00123; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Departure, MS007.001.001.00124; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 046. revision in 8:051
  - A fancy, MS007.001.001.00125; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - At the end, MS007.001.001.00126; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - The eyesore, MS007.001.001.00127; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 046. Annotated revision in 8:051
  - The candle, MS007.001.001.00128; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 048.
  - An intruder, MS007.001.001.00129; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Counterpoint, MS007.001.001.00130; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 049.
  - The street car, MS007.001.001.00131; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Equality, MS007.001.001.00132; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Petulant, MS007.001.001.00133; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 050. duplicate in 9:026
  - On a hillside, MS007.001.001.00134; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 050.
  - Gifts, MS007.001.001.00135; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 050. Revision located in 6:015 is handwritten revisions in 6:015 and 9:026
  - An old man tells a story, MS007.001.001.00136; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 051.
  - Peccavi, MS007.001.001.00137; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Old groping, MS007.001.001.00138; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Make believe, MS007.001.001.00139; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - Josita's banjo song, MS007.001.001.00140; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 052.
  - Let it be said, MS007.001.001.00141; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 052. Annotated. Duplicate in 10:034, p. 92 is handwritten. revisions in 9:073 and 10:034, p. 92; duplicate in 10:034, p. 91
  - A yonge manne; an olde tale, MS007.001.001.00142; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 053.
  - The cantadours pass by, MS007.001.001.00143; Holmes, John (Box 1)
  - I sing, MS007.001.001.00144; Holmes, John (Box 1)
    Box 1 folder 053. revision in 9:026